goeuro.com 2019-01-15

# Privacy Policy | GoEuro

The operator of the GoEuro websites and mobile apps as well as the “controller” in terms of the data protection legislation is the GoEuro Corp., registered in Delaware, USA, under No. 4973690. GoEuro Corp. has its operational headquarters at Schönhauser Allee 180, in 10119 Berlin. You can contact us at info@goeuro.com and our data protection officer at privacy@goeuro.com.

We want to inform you about our processing of your personal data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG). 

I. What kind of data do we collect? 

######  1\. Automatically generated website visitor information 

We collect information and data that is automatically transmitted or generated by your browser each time you visit our website. Such information includes the IP address, the URLs of the site you visited before accessing our website (“referrer”), the browser used, the browser language, the operating system and user interface, the access device used, date and time of your access, the pages viewed on our website, and the time you spend on the website. Such data is stored for a period of two years and deleted automatically thereafter. 

######  2\. Data provided by you / user accounts 

Furthermore, we also collect and use the information you provide to us about yourself and about the planning of your trip by using our services:

a) When you book a travel product through our service sites, we ask you to provide personal data, e.g. your name, your email address, phone number, billing address, payment method or credit card information, your preferred travel connection and – where applicable – information about your bonus or discount cards (e.g. mileage or frequent-flyer programmes, railway customer cards). We will only ever ask you for the data that the respective transportation provider requires to complete the booking process. Our forms show what kind of data is required for the respective booking. We cannot process your booking without provision of the required data. Credit card information will be immediately passed on to the respective payment provider. We only store truncated credit card data (e.g. “511111******1111”) for reporting purposes and fraud analysis. 

We store booking-related data for a period of 10 years and thereafter keep the information required by trade and tax law for the statutory retention periods (usually ten years after the conclusion of the contract / booking). 

b) Should you additionally register for a personal profile with GoEuro by creating a user account, this data will be stored with us for your future bookings

We keep your account data as long as you keep up your user account with us. If you decide to delete your account, we delete the associated data. However, potential booking data and related basic data (e.g. your name and address) will be kept as described above. 

c) If you contact us or our customer support (e.g. by email, telephone or contact form on the website), we use the data you provided (usually your contact information and your inquiry) to respond. We keep your inquiries for a period of five year after answering. To the extent required by trade or tax law, we keep such correspondence for the statutory retention periods (usually six years).

######  3\. Logging in with Facebook Connect or Google+ 

It will also be possible to log into our site using Facebook Connect or Google+. Doing so does not require you to register a separate user account with us. Instead, you can log in using your Facebook or Google login. In the process, Facebook or Google transmit certain personal data to us. Facebook will inform you during registration about the data to be transmitted (Facebook data). You will be given the opportunity to consent explicitly or to refuse. Facebook will not transmit any personal data to us without your permission. We will then be able to see your Facebook username and your public Facebook profile. We will use this data solely for the purposes detailed in this privacy policy. Conversely, Facebook will be able to see whether and when you log into our site using Facebook Connect. All of this applies equally for any logins via Google. 

You can stop using Facebook Connect or the Google+ login at any time and, if desired, create your own user account with us or use our services without a user account. 

######  4\. Newsletter and marketing emails 

If you have subscribed to our newsletter (e.g. by subscribing via the website or when creating a user account), we will send you a newsletter and marketing emails, including information about GoEuro and advertising for offers and services by us and third parties (e.g. travel, accommodation). 

You can **withdraw** your consent to receive such emails at any time for free e.g. by using the “unsubscribe” link in our emails. 

Upon withdrawal of your consent or unsubscribing from the newsletter, we delete your contact information, unless the contact information remains stored as part of your user account or in relation to bookings (see above).

######  5\. Cookies, web beacons and similar technology 

Like most other website operators, we use cookies, web beacons and suchlike when you visit our websites or use our services (“tracking facilities”).

Cookies are small text files that are stored by your browser on your computer or mobile device and which allow re-identification of your computer or mobile device, potentially across numerous websites. These cookies contain no personal data. Some of the cookies we use are deleted again upon expiry of the session, that is, when you close your browser (these are referred to as session cookies). Other cookies remain stored on your device and allow us, or our business partners to recognise your browser during subsequent visits (persistent cookies).

The use of cookies and similar methods allows us to collect information about users in order to provide simpler and more convenient access to our website or to provide certain services at all.

We use cookies and similar methods for the following purposes:

  * To save your user settings such as language and currency while on our websites and between visits.
  * To store your login status as a registered user (optional), so you do not have to log in again when returning to the website later.
  * For the technical assignment of your visit to certain servers to ensure a safe transition between pages and search queries.
  * To monitor the performance of our systems (no user-based evaluation of data).

Service providers for website analysis, retargeting and conversion tracking also use cookies (see below).

If you click a link on our websites that takes you to websites of other providers (for example when making a booking or to buy a ticket), it is possible that these other websites also store cookies on your computer. We have no control over these cookies and the data collected in this way and cannot accept any responsibility in that regard.

######  6\. Retargeting 

Our website uses what are known as retargeting tags for presentation of interest-related advertising on third-party websites. 

A retargeting tag is the name for a JavaScript element that is placed in our website’s source code. If you visit a page on our website that contains a retargeting tag, a provider of online advertising services (“retargeting provider”, e.g. Google, Facebook) places a cookie on your computer and allocates it to the corresponding retargeting target group lists. The retargeting provider uses the cookie to gather data related to your interests (e.g. the pages visited on the GoEuro website or search queries), using pseudonymous identifies. Based on that information, the retargeting provider displays interest-based ads on third party websites. No directly personally identifying data is stored or transmitted, and the usage profiles will not be merged with your personal data. However, the retargeting provider can potentially identify you and track your visits on our website, in particular, if you are a registered user of the retargeting provider (e.g. if you have a Google or Facebook account). 

We use the following retargeting providers: 

To learn more about this type of targeted advertising and your options for preventing it, follow this link: [youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)

You can object to usage-based online advertising by all or some providers on the same website. To access the preferences manager, click here: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement>

You can also prevent data transfer to all retargeting providers by GoEuro at any time by clicking the following link: 

When you click the link we will set a persistent cookie that allows us to recognize and observe your opt-out upon later visits to our website. Please note that it must be re-set when you delete all cookies in your browser. Opt-out cookies prevent tracking when you visit our website with a specific device, browser and domain. To prevent cookies on different devices or browsers, you have to set the opt-out cookie by clicking the opt-out button on all devices/browsers. The same applies if you visit our website under different top level domains (e.g. goeuro.com/goeuro.de). To prevent tracking in the app, please use the app’s opt-out function (see below). 

######  7\. Conversion tracking 

We use advertising partners to advertise our offers on third party websites. We also use marketing tools to determine the success of our advertising measures (“conversion tracking”). We intend to show you advertising relevant to your interests, to optimize our website and achieve a fair calculation of advertising costs. 

To that end our advertising partners use cookies and web beacons (see above) to measure certain parameters related to the success of an advertising campaign, e.g. display of an ad or user clicks. The cookies are not intended to personally identify you. For the lifetime of the cookie the advertising partner can identify your clicks on an ad and your redirection to a certain landing page (e.g. form input, confirmation page, newsletter subscription). Based on this information, the advertising partner generates conversion statistics. These statistics show e.g. the number of users that have clicked on one of our ads. In addition, the statistics show the number of users that have reached a certain target page that has been marked with a “conversion tag” (remarketing tag, see above). The statistics do not include data that allows us to personally identify you. 

We do not collect or use personal data in the advertising campaigns ourselves. Our advertising partners only provide us with statistical data, which allows us to identify effective advertising campaigns. We do not receive additional data, in particular no data that would allow us to identify our users.

Due to the conversion tracking tools your browser automatically connects to the server of the advertising partners. We have no influence on the scope and further use of data collected by the conversion tracking tools of our advertising partners. The advertising partners receive the information that you have visited certain pages on our website or clicked on one of our ads. If you are a registered user of the advertising partner (e.g. if you have a Google or Facebook account), the advertising partner can relate your visits to such account data. Even if you are not a registered user with the advertising partner, or are not logged into your account, the advertising partner may collect and store your IP address.

We use conversion tracking with the following advertising partners:

To learn more about this type of targeted advertising and your options for preventing it, follow this link: [youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)

You can object to usage-based online advertising by all or some providers on the same website. To access the preferences manager, click here: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement>

You can also prevent data transfer to all conversion tracking providers by GoEuro at any time by clicking the following link: 

When you click the link we will set a persistent cookie that allows us to recognize and observe your opt-out upon later visits to our website. Please note that it must be re-set when you delete all cookies in your browser. Opt-out cookies prevent tracking when you visit our website with a specific device, browser and domain. To prevent cookies on different devices or browsers, you have to set the opt-out cookie by clicking the opt-out button on all devices/browsers. The same applies if you visit our website under different top level domains (e.g. goeuro.com/goeuro.de). To prevent tracking in the app, please use the app’s opt-out function (see below).

###### 8\. Web analytics and statistics / Google Analytics

On our websites, we use "Google Analytics", a web analytics service provided by Google LLC. (“Google”). Google uses cookies (see above), which are stored on the user's computer and allow us to analyse the use of our website. The information generated by the cookie about the use, including the user’s current, but truncated IP address are transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Since we have activated IP anonymization, your IP address will be truncated by Google within a European Union member state or a member state of the European Economic Area before transmission to the USA. Only in exceptional circumstances will the full IP address be transferred and truncated in the USA. Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our website, compiling reports on the activities of users of our services, and to provide other services associated with Internet use. In addition, Google may also transfer this information to third parties if required to do so by law or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. The IP address sent by your browser to Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data.

You can prevent the installation of cookies by changing the settings of your browser. Please note, however, that this may prevent some of our services’ feature from working correctly. Alternatively you can prevent the collection of cookie data and your website usage data (including your IP address) by Google and the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing a browser plugin available at: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

In addition, you can disable data processing by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link:  
Deactivate Google Analytics

This sets an opt-out cookie that prevents the future collection of your data when visiting our website. Please note that it must be reset when you delete all cookies in your browser.

This website utilizes Google Analytics with the extension “_anonymizeIP()”. This ensures processing of truncated IP addresses, so that no direct personal identification via IP addresses is possible.

Personal data associated with cookies, user identifiers (e.g., User-ID) and advertising identifiers (e.g., DoubleClick cookies, Android’s Advertising ID, Apple’s Identifier for Advertisers) will be deleted automatically after 14 months.

Use of Google Analytics is in accordance with the requirements agreed between the German data protection authorities and Google. Please find additional information here: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001. Usage terms: http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html, Privacy information: http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html, Privacy policy: http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy.

Google is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

###### 9\. Social Plugins

Our website uses what are referred to as social plugins by the following social media providers:

We use the so-called 2-click solution. If you visit our website, no personal data is transferred to the plugin provider. You can recognize the plugin provider by the label or logo on the button. We permit you to communicate directly with the plugin provider via the button.

Only if you click the button and activate the plugin, the plugin provider receives the information that you have visited the respective page of our website. In addition, the information mentioned under Sec. 1 above is transferred by your browser to the plugin provider. If you have an account with the plugin provider, and are logged in, the provider may relate your visit to our website and your additional interaction with the social plugin (e.g. clicking on the “Like” button) to your user account (e.g. your Facebook account).

We have no influence on the data collected and processed by the plugin provider, nor do we know the full extent of the data processing, purposes, retention terms and deletion of data by the plugin provider. Please find additional information regarding data processing by the plugin provider in the privacy policies linked above. These policies also include information regarding your rights and privacy-related configuration options.

II. GoEuro app 

The GoEuro app is an alternative way to access offers by GoEuro. The GoEuro app in principle records, processes and utilizes data in the same way as the GoEuro website, for the same purposes and on the same legal basis. The contents of this privacy policy thus apply accordingly. 

###### 1\. Additional use of app-specific data

When using the app, GoEuro can access additional data relating to the app or your mobile device, e.g. the device name, device manufacturer, model, operating system version, app version or SDK version and the device number (IMEI), advertising identifiers (e.g. Android’s Advertising ID, Apple’s Identifier for Advertisers). If you are using an Android device, the app can also detect what Google services you have subscribed to and can prevent your device from going into standby while the app is running. 

We record your device’s current location to use it for processing your query (filling in your location in the search form). Your position data is transmitted through an encrypted connection. If you use GPS, the app will detect your precise location. However, both Android and iOS apps require you to grant permission first. The data is used to fill in the search form and will not be stored otherwise. 

###### 2\. Statistics and analytics

We use data analytics services to create statistics and analytics regarding the use of the app and our services, and the transition to our partner’s websites or services. In particular, we use the IP address and device identifier of your mobile device for such purposes. In addition, we may use such information to create cross-device, pseudonymous usage profiles (“cross-device-tracking”). You can disable the analytics functionality at any time in the GoEuro app preferences.

In our apps, we use "Google Analytics" and “Firebase Analytics” as analytics services provided by Google LLC. (“Google”). Google provides SDKs (software development kits), which are stored on the user's device and allow us to analyse the use of our app. The information generated by the SDKs about the use, including the user’s current, but truncated IP address, are transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Since we have activated IP anonymization, your IP address will be truncated by Google within a European Union member state or a member state of the European Economic Area before transmission to the USA. Only in exceptional circumstances will the full IP address be transferred and truncated in the USA. Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our app, compiling reports on the activities of users of our services and to provide other services associated with Internet use. In addition, Google may also transfer this information to third parties if required to do so by law or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. The IP address sent by your app to Google Analytics or Firebase will not be merged with other Google data. 

If you are using the app, you can disable data processing by Google Analytics or by Firebase by using the switch at the bottom of this page.

This app utilizes Google Analytics with the extension “_anonymizeIP()”. This ensures processing of truncated IP addresses, so that no direct personal identification via IP addresses is possible.

Please find additional information regarding Google Analytics here: Usage terms: http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html, Privacy information: http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html, Privacy policy: http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy.

Google is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

###### 3\. Push messages

If you have configured your mobile device accordingly, the GoEuro app will be able to send you push messages, e.g. to provide updates on GoEuro, status updates, campaigns and other news, or to notify you of new features. Push messages may also include advertising for GoEuro or third party offers (e.g. travel, accommodation).

You can withdraw your consent to receive marketing push messages at any time free of charge e.g. by disabling marketing push messages in the app or deactivating push messages in your operating system preferences.

We use Braze, 114 Sansome St Suite 1200, San Francisco, CA 9410, to send newsletters and push notifications based on your searches. You can find more information regarding data processing by Braze and your rights and options with regard to protecting your personal data here: <https://www.braze.com/privacy/>

###### 4\. Retargeting

You can find more information about retargeting above (Sec. I.6).

We use the following retargeting and attribution providers:

Provider | Contact | Further information  
---|---|---  
Adjust | adjust Inc. 500 Montgomery Street, Suite A, San Francisco, CA 94111, USA | Your Adjust ID (a unique identifier) and the routes you have searched for will be sent to Adjust (an attribution tool). These are solely used for pseudonymous analytics and are not related to a natural person. You can find additional information regarding data processing by Adjust and your rights and options with regard to protecting your personal data here: <https://www.adjust.com/privacy-policy/>  
Liftoff Mobile, Inc | 555 Bryant Street, Suite 133, Palo Alto, CA 94301, USA | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of optimization of our marketing measures (conversion optimization).  
Criteo SA | 32,Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris |   
Click Tech Limited (Yeahmobi) | Room 1907, 19/F, Lee Garden One, 33 Hysan Av, Causeway Bay, Hong Kong | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of optimization of our marketing measures (conversion optimization).  
Taptica LTD | 121 Ha´chashmonaim street, Tel Aviv - Israel 6713328 | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of optimization of our marketing measures (conversion optimization).  
Inmobi Pte. Ltd | 30 Cecile Street, 19-08 Prudential Tower Singapore, 049712 | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of optimization of our marketing measures (conversion optimization).  
AppNext Ltd | Intershore Chambers, Road Town, Tortola, British Virgin Island | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of optimization of our marketing measures (conversion optimization).  
Jampp LTD | Studio 103, 242 Acklam Road, London, UK 110 5 JJ | Processes information in order to display interest-based advertising based on inferred interests or preferences. Also processes information in aggregated form for the purposes of performance and service improvement and fraud prevention.  
TIRBURTINA S.A. /Lemmonet | Avda. Rivera 7043 - Montevideo, Uruguay, 11500 | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of optimization of our marketing measures (conversion optimization).  
Adperio | 2000 S. Colorado Blvd Tower 1 Suite 7000, Denver, CO 80222, USA | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of conversion optimization.  
Remerge GmbH  | Oranienburger Straße 27, 10117 Berlin | Processes information in order to display interest-based advertising based on inferred interests or preferences. Also processes information in aggregated form for the purposes of performance and service improvement and fraud prevention.  
Stroeer Mobile Performance GmbH | Erftstraße 19 a, 50672 Cologne | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of conversion optimization.  
Branch | 1400 Seaport Blvd Building B, 2nd Floor Redwood City, CA 94063 USA | Branch collects your phone number when you interact with the "text me the ticket" feature. This feature will make sure you receive an SMS showing how to download the app with the ticket pre-loaded. This happens on mobile web or on desktop web interfaces.  
Myappfree S.R.L.  | Via Selice 84/A, Imola, 40026 (BO) Italy | Collects anonymous information when you interact with the app for the purpose of conversion optimization.  
  
If you are using the app, you can prevent data transfer to all retargeting providers at any time by using the switch at the bottom of this page.

When clicking the opt-out switch we will disable the SDKs that allow us to recognize you. We will observe your opt-out upon later use of our app. The opt-out switch prevents tracking when you use our app. To prevent tracking or retargeting on the website, you have to set the opt-out cookie by clicking the opt-out button in your browser.

III. Data recipients 

###### 1\. Data processing by GoEuro Travel GmbH 

GoEuro Corp. employs GoEuro Travel GmbH, Schönhauser Allee 180, 10119 Berlin, Germany as a service provider to, among other things, operate computer systems, handle order processing and perform customer service. 

GoEuro Travel GmbH is a subsidiary of GoEuro Corp. Your personal data will be forwarded to GoEuro Travel GmbH or collected directly by GoEuro Travel GmbH on behalf of GoEuro Corp. GoEuro Travel GmbH will process your data solely in accordance with this privacy policy and only for the purposes of performing services for GoEuro Corp., in particular for running the GoEuro platform and providing associated services. This privacy information therefore applies to data processing by GoEuro Travel GmbH as well. You can contact GoEuro Travel GmbH’s data protection officer at privacy@goeuro.com.

We contractually oblige GoEuro Travel GmbH to observe the provisions of this privacy information, to process your data for the aforementioned purposes only and to observe all applicable data protection and data security law and regulations.

###### 2\. Data transmission related to bookings

###### a) Transportation provider

If you make a booking on our websites, we will transmit any personal data required to the respective transportation provider (e.g. airline, railway or coach operator, hire car company, hotel) so that the transportation provider can process your booking and produce any personalized tickets that may be required. Such a third party will then process your personal data under its own responsibility and in accordance with its own privacy policies.

Bookings may be handled by our subsidiary GoEuro Voyages SAS. In such cases we transmit the required data to GoEuro Voyages SAS, which processes the data on our behalf and only for the purposes of completing the booking process.

Bookings for certain countries (at the moment Russia, Ukraine and Poland) are handled by our partner Amadeus IT Group SA (Salvador de Madariaga 1, Madrid, 28027, Spain) and its affiliated companies. For such purposes we transmit your booking data to Amadeus, which processes the data under its own responsibility according to their data protection policy http://www.amadeus.com/web/amadeus/en_1A-corporate/Amadeus-Home/Amadeus_IT_Group_SA-Legal-notices-2014/1319560218660-Page-AMAD_Detail_PopUp_Ppal?assetid=1319607040997&assettype=DataProtection_C#gds-privacy. 

This data transfer requires that your explicit consent is given for each booking process, pursuant to Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR.

###### b) Payment providers

The payment details (credit card information) for bookings made directly on our website are processed by a trusted Internet payment processor, who will transmit your data directly to the relevant credit card company. 

In order to ensure that the credit card is used by the legitimate owner and to prevent cases of online fraud, encrypted credit card information is transferred to an external payment security service for auditing purposes. This transfer may also include additional personal data.

Your credit card data is processed by trusted and reliable Internet payment processors. Your credit card details are encrypted (usually using the SSL protocol) before transmission to the payment processor. Your credit card data will not be disclosed to us by the payment processors.

###### c) Accommodation providers

In addition, basic information relating to your query (e.g. destination and travel dates) will be transmitted to the accommodation providers shown in the search window (e.g. booking.com or airbnb), but only if you included the respective accommodation provider in your query by checking a box. You will then see non-binding offers from the provider matching your search query in a new window or tab. This does not entail transmission on our part of any personal data (except for the IP address).

###### 3\. Other service providers

We may use third party service providers, in particular for technical and business services, tax advisors and legal counsel. This may include hosting providers, including a content delivery network to cache and provide content, statistics and analytics, providers to handle service desk and support data, provision of CRM systems, sending of newsletters/mailings, spam and fraud prevention, IT service and development providers.

These service providers receive personal data solely for the performance of their services for us on our behalf. They are contractually obliged not to use personal data for other purposes.

###### 4\. Recipients outside of the EU

The data processing mentioned under Sec. I2a, I6-9, II2,3, III2,3 may result in data transmission to recipients outside of the EU. The data transmission is then based on the privacy shield (https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome) or based on the EC model contracts (http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm).

Personal information may be transferred to transportation providers located in non-EU countries, in which the travel is scheduled to take place. GoEuro cannot provide any further information on the level of data protection offered in third countries. Neither an adequacy decision in accordance with Art. 45 para. 3 GDPR or appropriate safeguards in accordance with Art 46 GDPR are required for the transfer as it is necessary

  * for the performance of a contract between you and GoEuro or the implementation of pre-contractual measures taken at your request (Art. 49(1)(b) GDPR); or
  * for the conclusion or performance of a contract concluded in your interest between GoEuro and another natural or legal person (Art. 49(1)(c) GDPR).

IV. Purposes and legal basis of data processing 

We process your personal data for the following purposes and on the following legal basis: 

a) Pursuant to Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR to enter into, perform, modify or terminate a contractual relationship with you, in particular:

  * to enable your access to and visit of the website and use of the app,
  * to facilitate your search queries and bookings,
  * to perform our contractual obligations,
  * to personalize your ticket or booking and to contact you with regards to the booking process or your user account, for example to send you the travel documents,
  * to facilitate your login on our website or the app (user account functionality), to recognize you as a user and spare you from re-entering your data upon your revisits to our sites.

b) Pursuant to Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR based on our legitimate interests,

  * to improve our website, apps and services and adapt them to the needs of our users,
  * to perform internal quality checks,
  * to prevent, detect, process and investigate malfunctions, incidents, fraudulent or other illegal activities, or mitigate the risk of occurrence of the aforementioned events,
  * to ensure network and information security,
  * to prevent fraud,
  * to create statistics on access channels, the use of our website and app and the transition to our partner’s websites and services,
  * for internal accounting and invoicing purposes with the respective transportation providers, partners and service providers,
  * to personalize our website and offers,
  * to display advertisements and special offers that may match your interests (or spare you the display of advertising and special offers which would likely not be of any interest to you),
  * for marketing purposes and to optimize our marketing measures,
  * to enable your interaction with social networks and other users, in order to improve our offer and make it more interesting for our users, to contact you, if requested by you or if necessary to fulfil the contract or permitted by law,
  * for the purpose of business process outsourcing to affiliated companies,
  * enforcing obligations owed to us, and contractual terms and conditions,
  * accounting, risk management and record keeping.

c) Pursuant to Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR based on your consent,

  * to send you emails or push messages about GoEuro, status notifications, news, new functionality or offers of GoEuro third parties (e.g. travel, accommodation),
  * \- to transfer data for certain bookings to our partner Amadeus (see above).

d) Pursuant to Art. 6(1)(c) GDPR to comply with legal obligations, e.g. to observe retention periods required by trade or tax law or to comply with obligations to disclose data based on a legally binding court decision or official order.

V. Rights of the data subject, right to lodge complaints, right to object 

In addition to the right to revoke your consent given to us, if applicable, you have the right to request access to (Art. 15 GDPR) and rectification (Art. 16 GDPR) or erasure (Art. 17 GDPR) of personal data or restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR), the right to object (Art. 21 GDPR) and the right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR). 

You have the right to object to all types of processing described in this privacy information that are based on Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR, based on grounds relating to your particular situation (Art. 21(1) GDPR). 

To the extent we process your personal data pursuant to Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR for direct marketing purposes, you can object to such processing at any time without giving a particular reason. 

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR). The competent supervisory authority for GoEuro is:

Berliner Beauftragte für Datenschutz und Informationsfreiheit

Friedrichstr. 219, 10969 Berlin, Germany  
Fax: +49 (0)30 2155050  
E-Mail: mailbox@datenschutz-berlin.de
